<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course Introduction &amp; Tools on JavaScript</title>
    <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Course Introduction &amp; Tools on JavaScript</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/00-course-intro-and-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Objectives</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/objectives/</guid>
      <description> Cover class logistics, structure &amp;amp; keys to success
 Introduce tools you will be using throughout the class
 Discuss the benchmarks for assessments in terms of class participation, homework, and unit projects
 Confirm installation and configuration of Node, Git, and other command line tools
 Practice programmatic thinking by writing pseudocode
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Logistics &amp; Materials</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-logistics-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-logistics-materials/</guid>
      <description>Class Logistics  Class Schedule: Mondays &amp;amp; Wednesdays, 8:00pm - 11:00pm, from Jul 30th through Oct 3rd
 Break: 15 minute break during the middle of class from 9:15pm to 9:30pm (subject to change depending on flow of the class, but you&amp;rsquo;ll always get a 15 min break)
 Class Materials: Most lessons will include a set of files that you&amp;rsquo;ll work with during that lesson, we&amp;rsquo;ll refer to these files as the &amp;ldquo;lesson files&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Structure</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/course-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/course-structure/</guid>
      <description>Overview  The course has 20 classes
 What you&amp;rsquo;ll learn:
 Fundamentals of JavaScript: including programming concepts such as data types, variables, and loops—the core concepts of programming
 Object Oriented JavaScript (OOP) and APIs: Learn how JavaScript can be used to exchange information and functionality within our programs
 Practical applications of JavaScript: Learn how to JavaScript can be used to manipulate websites and applications
  3 Projects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Tools</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/tools/</guid>
      <description>Text Editor:
 Why?: Text editor is a program that developers use to create and edit a range of programming language files. We&amp;rsquo;ll be using Atom, because it&amp;rsquo;s open source (free) and really good.
 Download Atom
  Browser:
 Why?: Google chrome is a robust browser with a variety of tools that are helpful to developers.
 Install Google Chrome
  Github:
 Why?: Github (and Git) are tools/applications used to by developers to manage their code and work collaboratively with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folder Organization</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/folder-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/folder-structure/</guid>
      <description>Recommended Folder Organization  Create a folder in your Documents folder (My Documents on Windows) called jsr
 At beginning of every class, you&amp;rsquo;ll use git (this process will be explained in the next class) to download any starter files to your jsr folder are available for that day&amp;rsquo;s lesson
 As the course progresses you&amp;rsquo;ll have a neatly organized listing of all of your work that looks similar to this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirm Node &amp; Git Installation</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/confirm-node-git-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/confirm-node-git-installation/</guid>
      <description>Confirm Node &amp;amp; Git Installation 1) Ensure that you followed the installation instructions for your Operation System found here: Node and Git Installation
2) Open up your console / terminal
 For Mac OS X users:
 Open the &amp;ldquo;Terminal&amp;rdquo; app (Applications &amp;gt; Utilities &amp;gt; Terminal)  For Windows:
 Open the &amp;ldquo;Command Prompt&amp;rdquo; application.   3) In the terminal type the following command to confirm git was successfully installed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Programming?</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-programming/</guid>
      <description> What is Programming?  List of instructions that a computer needs in order to complete a task
 Instructions are provided in a programming language that the computer understands
 These set of instructions are commonly referred as source code or a program
 There are many programming languages available, during this course we will be learning JavaScript
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is JavaScript?</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-javascript/</guid>
      <description>What is JavaScript?  programming language created in 1995 by Netscape (now Mozilla)
 It was created in 10 days
 Not the same as Java
  What does JavaScript do?  Adds interactivity to your websites
 Makes web based software feel more like desktop software
 Can be used to save data to a database or to create desktop applications
 Improves overall user experience of web-based applications</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudocode</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/pseudocode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/pseudocode/</guid>
      <description> Pseudocode  Process of writing a program without using the syntax of a programming language
 Mixture of natural language and high-level programming concepts
 There is no standard way to write pseudocode, use langauge that can be understood by technical and non-technical people
 Use pseudocode as an &amp;ldquo;outline&amp;rdquo; for your real code
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Exercise - Smart Thermostat Pseudocode</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-exercise-smart-thermostat-pseudocode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-exercise-smart-thermostat-pseudocode/</guid>
      <description> Class Exercise: Thermostat logic in pseudocode We&amp;rsquo;re going to use pseudocode to describe the basic functionality of a smart thermostat
 As as class we are going to write some pseudocode for a program for a smart thermostat
 We’ll focus on coming up with the logic that will help the thermostat know when to turn the heat on and off
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Exercise - Rock, Paper, Scissors</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/group-exercise-rock-paper-scissors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/group-exercise-rock-paper-scissors/</guid>
      <description>Group Exercise: Rock, Paper and Scissors Form groups (of 2 or 3) and write pseudocode describing a game of Rock, Paper, Scissors</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>