<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Express on JavaScript</title>
    <link>/16-intro-to-express/express/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Express on JavaScript</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/16-intro-to-express/express/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/16-intro-to-express/express/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/16-intro-to-express/express/overview/</guid>
      <description> What is Express?  Express is a popular Node web framework that enables developers to build web servers (backend) that can respond to http requests and return data
 Outside of providing built-in support for routing, Express has minimal functionality of its own
 Functionality is added to an Express application through the use of Middleware
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Middleware</title>
      <link>/16-intro-to-express/express/middleware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/16-intro-to-express/express/middleware/</guid>
      <description>Middleware  Middleware functions are functions that have access to the request object (req), the response object (res), and the next middleware function in the application’s request-response cycle
 Middleware functions can perform the following tasks:
 Execute any code.
 Make changes to the request and the response objects.
 End the request-response cycle.
 Call the next middleware function in the stack
  An Express application is essentially a series of middleware function calls</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routing</title>
      <link>/16-intro-to-express/express/routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/16-intro-to-express/express/routing/</guid>
      <description>Routing  Routing refers to determining how an application responds to a client request to a particular endpoint, which is a URI (or path) and a specific HTTP request method (GET, POST, and so on)
 Each route can have one or more handler functions, which are executed when the route is matched
 Route definition takes the following structure:
  app.METHOD(PATH, HANDLER)   app is an instance of express.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Route Parameters</title>
      <link>/16-intro-to-express/express/route-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/16-intro-to-express/express/route-parameters/</guid>
      <description>Route Parameters  Route parameters are named URL segments that are used to capture the values specified at their position in the URL
 The captured values are populated in the req.params object, with the name of the route parameter specified in the path as their respective keys
 Route parameters are similar to function parameters
 Given the following route handler:
app.get(&#39;/users/:userId/books/:bookId&#39;, function (req, res) { res.send(req.params) })   If the client makes a request to the following url: GET http://localhost:3000/users/34/books/8989</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>