<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AJAX on JavaScript</title>
    <link>/09-http-and-apis/ajax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AJAX on JavaScript</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/09-http-and-apis/ajax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/09-http-and-apis/ajax/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/09-http-and-apis/ajax/overview/</guid>
      <description>What is AJAX?  AJAX stands for Asynchronous JavaScript And XML
 The meaning: Web clients can send or receive data to/from the server without requesting an entire page - instead, clients can just request or send an arbitrary amount of data
 In front-end development, AJAX is often used to make API requests that will fetch data from another service without having to refresh the web page
  Click here for more information about AJAX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AJAX Requests using Native JS</title>
      <link>/09-http-and-apis/ajax/ajax-request-native-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/09-http-and-apis/ajax/ajax-request-native-js/</guid>
      <description>Making AJAX Requests using Native JavaScript  JavaScript has a built-in object called XMLHttpRequest that can be used to make AJAX requests (i.e. Client-side HTTP requests made in the background which do not require a page refresh)
 XMLHttpRequest is not normally used due to large amount to code needed to make requests; libraries jQuery (using $.ajax(), $.get(), etc) and others are often used in place of XMLHttpRequest
  Example  Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of what an AJAX request using XMLHttpRequest looks like:  function logResponse(data) { console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AJAX Requests with jQuery</title>
      <link>/09-http-and-apis/ajax/ajax-request-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/09-http-and-apis/ajax/ajax-request-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Using $.ajax  jQuery offers an .ajax() method that can be used to make API calls
 Example of an AJAX call using jQuery&amp;rsquo;s $.ajax method
  $.ajax({ url: &amp;#39;some/url/specified/by/api&amp;#39;, type: &amp;#34;GET&amp;#34;, data: { name: &amp;#39;bob&amp;#39; } }) .done(() =&amp;gt; { // execute this function if request is successful  console.log(data) }) .fail(() =&amp;gt; { // execute this function if request fails  alert(&amp;#39;error occurred&amp;#39;) })  $.ajax() properties Here are some of the commonly used properties of the $.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>