<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Class Resources on JavaScript</title>
    <link>/class-resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Class Resources on JavaScript</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/class-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>/class-resources/office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/office-hours/</guid>
      <description>Weekly Office Hours Weekly, the instructional team will hold office online
 Day / Time:
 Thursdays, 8:30 PM ET to 10:30 PM ET
 Mondays, 7:00 PM ET to 8:00 PM ET
 Wednesdays, 7:00 PM ET to 8:00 PM ET
  Location: Online via Zoom (link will be provided in Slack prior the start of office hours)
 Policy: No prior sign up required, just log drop in if you have questions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>/class-resources/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/documentation/</guid>
      <description>Referencing documentation is a core task for developers.
 Documentation communicates how something (in our case programming languages, software libraries) works.
 Good documentation reduces implementation time and increases predictability of our software programs.
  We will be referring to the following list of the documentation resources frequently throughout the course:
HTML MDN&amp;rsquo;s HTML Reference
CSS MDN&amp;rsquo;s CSS Reference
JavaScript MDN&amp;rsquo;s JavaScript Reference
jQuery jQuery Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Commands</title>
      <link>/class-resources/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>The following is a summary of the most commonly used git commands
Create Repositories Start a new repository or obtain one from an existing URL
   Command Description     git init Creates a new local repository in the current directory   git init [project-name] Creates a new local repository with the specified name   git clone [url] Downloads a project and its entire version history    Making Changes    Command Description     git status Lists all new or modified files to be committed   git add [file] Snapshots the file in preparation for versioning   git commit -m &amp;quot;[descriptive message]&amp;quot; Records file snapshots permanently in version history   git diff Shows file differences not yet staged   git diff --staged Shows file differences between staging and the last file version   git reset [file] Unstages the file, but preserve its contents    Working with Branches    Command Description     git branch Lists all local branches in the current repository   git branch [branch-name] Creates a new branch   git checkout [branch-name] Switches to the specified branch and updates the working directory   git merge [branch] Combines the specified branch’s history into the current branch   git branch -d [branch-name] Deletes the specified branch    Review History    Command Description     git log Lists version history for the current branch   git log --follow [file] Lists version history for a file, including renames   git show [commit] Outputs metadata and content changes of the specified commit   git diff [first-branch].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Workflow for Submitting Assignments</title>
      <link>/class-resources/git-workflow-submitting-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/git-workflow-submitting-assignments/</guid>
      <description>Step 0: Fork the Assignment Repository  This step is only done once per project
 Every assignment will be accompanied by repository url on GitHub
 Click on the provided url and then fork the repository
   Step 1: Clone the project down to your computer  This step is only done once per project
 While on the repository page of the forked repository, click on the &amp;ldquo;Clone or Download&amp;rdquo; button</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
      <link>/class-resources/keyboard-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 18:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/keyboard-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>General Window Management &amp;amp; Browser Shortcuts    Action Mac Windows     Open Chrome Developer Tools cmd+option + i F2 or ctrl + shift + i   Refresh page cmd + R ctrl + R   Switch between applications cmd + tab alt + tab   Switch between windows in the same application cmd + ~     Atom Shortcuts Files, Windows, Tabs Management    Command macOS Windows Linux Description     Open Settings Menu cmd+, ctrl+, ctrl+, Opens the Atom&amp;rsquo;s settings menu   Open File (Fuzzy) cmd+p or cmd+t ctrl+p or ctrl+t ctrl+p or ctrl+t Opens the Fuzzy Finder   Browse Open Files cmd+b ctrl+b ctrl+b Browse tabs within the window   Previous Tab alt+cmd+left ctrl+pageup ctrl+pageup Cycles left through open tabs (in the active pane)   Next Tab alt+cmd+right ctrl+pagedown ctrl+pagedown Cycles right through open tabs (in the active page)   Toggle Tree View cmd+\ ctrl+\ ctrl+\ Toggles Atom&amp;rsquo;s file Tree View   Show Available Snippets alt+shift+s alt+shift+s alt+shift+s Shows the snippets available to Atom   Save cmd+s ctrl+s ctrl+s Saves the currently active file   Save As shift+cmd+s ctrl+shift+s ctrl+shift+s Saves the currently active file under a different name   Save All alt+cmd+s   Saves all changed files   Close Tab cmd+w ctrl+w ctrl+w Closes the currently active tab   Close Window shift+cmd+w ctrl+shift+w ctrl+shift+w Closes the currently active editor window   Split Window cmd+k up/down/left/right ctrl+k up/down/left/right ctrl+k up/down/left/right Split the currently active tab in one of the four directions   Focus Pane cmd+k cmd+up/down/left/right ctrl+k ctrl+up/down/left/right ctrl+k ctrl+up/down/left/right Move the focus to the pane in one of the four directions   Toggle full screen ctrl+cmd+f F11 F11 Toggle full screen window    Editing    Command macOS Windows Linux Description     Duplicate Lines shift+cmd+d ctrl+shift+d ctrl+shift+d Duplicates the line of the current cursor position and creates a new line under it with the same contents   Delete Line ctrl+shift+k ctrl+shift+k ctrl+shift+k Deletes the current line   Move Line Up ctrl+cmd+up ctrl+up ctrl+up Moves the contents of the current cursor position up one line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Atom Editor Settings</title>
      <link>/class-resources/atom-editor-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/atom-editor-settings/</guid>
      <description>All of the settings below can be accessed using the following steps:
 Mac: cmd + , -&amp;gt; Editor PC: ctrl + , -&amp;gt; Editor  Setting indentation levels / default tab-size During our course we will be using a set indentation level of 2 spaces (1 indentation level = 2 spaces). Atom makes it easy conform to this approach by setting our tab to a set level of indentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening Atom from Command Line</title>
      <link>/class-resources/opening-atom-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/opening-atom-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>Atom allows you to open files from the command line
If you have Atom installed you can run the atom command with one or more file paths to open up those files in Atom.
Check if Atom is already configured to run on your computer&amp;rsquo;s Command Line Open up your terminal and run the following command
$ atom --help  You should receive output similar to the following
Atom Editor v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Atom Themes</title>
      <link>/class-resources/atom-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/atom-themes/</guid>
      <description>Changing Themes Atom allows you to easily switch between your installed themes by doing the following:
 Opening Atom Settings (mac: cmd + , | pc: ctrl + ,) Select Themes in the left-hand menu Select the dropdown menu labeled Syntax Themes Choose one of the installed themes listed in the dropdown menu  Atom comes pre-installed with a set of themes. See that section below to add new themes to Atom</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show Git-Ignored Files in Atom</title>
      <link>/class-resources/atom-show-git-ignored-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/atom-show-git-ignored-files/</guid>
      <description> Show Git-Ignored Files in Atom Atom, by default, will not show files in its file pane (file tree view) if those files have been added to .gitignore.
An easy approach to fixing this issue is to do the following:
 Click anywhere in the Tree View (left hand pane with files and folders) Press i (this will toggle the visibility of hidden files)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Success</title>
      <link>/class-resources/keys-to-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 17:11:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/keys-to-success/</guid>
      <description>Do your homework: More you practice the concepts learned in class, the faster you&amp;rsquo;ll pick them up
 Don&amp;rsquo;t try to memorize anything: You&amp;rsquo;ll memorize things naturally through the act of doing things over and over again. Besides, if you don&amp;rsquo;t remember something just look it up (i.e. google).
 Work smarter not harder: In additional to looking things up, developers are really good at referencing past code that they&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to solve problems they encounter in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning HTML &amp; CSS</title>
      <link>/class-resources/learning-html-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/learning-html-css/</guid>
      <description>Here are some great (FREE) resources for learning HTML &amp;amp; CSS
HTML &amp;amp; CSS  Codecademy - HTML &amp;amp; CSS course
 Shay Howe - Learn to Code HTML &amp;amp; CSS
 FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design Certification (300 hours)
 Udacity - Intro to HTML and CSS
 Khan Academy - Intro to HTML/CSS
  Flexbox  MDN - Flexbox
 Flexbox - Flexbox Froggy
 Flexbox - Flexbox Zombies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CORS</title>
      <link>/class-resources/cors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class-resources/cors/</guid>
      <description> CORS  CORS is the policy that defines this, an acronym that stands for &amp;ldquo;Cross-Origin Resource Sharing&amp;rdquo;
 You cannot normally make an AJAX request across different domains
 Some domains don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to ping them from other domains and some do
  Click here for more information about CORS
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>